-大伙们，你们猜怎么了？ -什么？
-Guys,guess what? -What?
我们要办万圣节派对
We're having a Halloween party!
-很好 -太棒了
-Good! -Great!
-你们得变装 -我没办法参加
-You have to wear a costume. -I can't make it.
少来了，一定会很好玩的
Come on,it'll be fun.
我会去的 反正那天上课时我也要变装
I'll be there. I have to wear a costume to my classes that day anyway.
告诉我 你不会打扮成恐龙
Tell me you're not gonna dress like a dinosaur.
我不会连续两年那么做
Not two years in a row.
-我会去的，但我不会变装 -你得变装才行
-I'll come,but I'm not dressing up. -You have to.
不，万圣节太愚蠢了 变装，假装你是另一个人
No. Halloween is stupid. Dressing up,pretending to be someone you're not.
你是个演员
You're an actor.
罗斯，你会带蒙娜来吗？
Ross,are you gonna bring Mona?
-我会的 -你在婚礼上认识的那个女孩？
-I will. -The girl from the wedding?
如果她需要变装建议 她可以扮成比基尼模特儿…
If she needs costume ideas,she could be a bikini model..
或风流护士 或性感啦啦队长
or a slutty nurse,or a sexy cheerleader.
或是《德州电锯杀人狂》里的人皮脸 不，还是风流皮脸好了
Or Leatherface from Texas Chainsaw Massacre. No! Slutty Leatherface.
乔伊不也很喜欢她吗？
Wasn't Joey hitting on her too?
没错，他喜欢她
That's right,he was hitting on her.
我把到她了 我猜最好的男人才能赢
And I got her. I guess the better man won.
拜托别把她抢走
Please don't take her from me.
本集播出：万圣节派对
The.One.With.The.Halloween.Party
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
主演：寇妮考克斯
主演：丽莎库卓
主演：麦特勒布兰
主演：马修派瑞
主演：大卫修蒙
乌苏拉
Ursula!
等一下，是我，我是菲比
Wait. It's me,Phoebe.
我还以为那里有镜子 好吧，再见
I thought there was a mirror there. Okay. Bye.
等一下
Wait a second!
你还好吗？
So,what's new with you?
我很好 下星期我就要结婚了
Nothing. I'm getting married next week.
什么？
What?
婚礼很简单 我们只邀请家人观礼
It'll be a small ceremony. Just family.
他的家人
His.
好吧
Okay.
我为你感到高兴
I'm happy for you.
等一下，如果你也想来的话 我猜应该没关系
Wait. If you want to come,I guess that'd be okay.
-真的吗？ -当然
-Really? -Sure.
你可以当我的妹妹一天
You could be my sister for the day.
好吧
Yeah,okay.
我朋友今晚要办派对 你可以来参加
My friends are having a party tonight,so you could come.
或许我可以看看他
Maybe I could meet the guy.
我今晚要上班
Well,I'm supposed to work tonight.
我现在应该去上班 谁在乎呢？
I'm supposed to be working now,so who cares!
-那是化装派对 -所以你才会…
-It's a costume party. -So that's why you're..
不
No.
但谢谢
But thanks.
-你应该变装的 -我有啊
-You're supposed to wear a costume. -I am.
我扮成花钱 买心爱礼服的女人…
I am a woman who spent money on a dress she wants to wear..
因为很快地 她会穿不下它
because soon she won't fit into it.
我是猫女（蝙蝠侠中的角色）如果你穿不下它，可以把它送给我
I'm Catwoman,who wants the dress when you're too big for it.
-不给糖就捣蛋 -我可以分糖果给他们吗？
-Trick or treat! -Can I give out candy?
我想跟孩子们打成一片 我怀孕后母性的直觉都跑出来了
I want to be with kids. Since I got pregnant,I have maternal instincts.
-不给糖就捣蛋 -等一下
-Trick or treat! -Just a minute!
看看你们
Look at you guys!
-哇，你是个可怕的巫婆 -谢谢
-Wow! You are a very scary witch. -Thank you.
-你是个好笑的小丑 -谢谢
-And you are a very funny clown. -Thank you.
你…
And you..
非常符合现在的流行趋势
are so in style right now.
我在罗夫罗兰的公司工作 今年秋天流行马术主题
I work at Ralph Lauren. The fall line has got this equestrian theme.
-你看过时尚杂志的封面… -我可以拿糖果吗？
-Did you see the cover of Vogue..? -Could I just have the candy?
没问题
Sure.
猫女，我们又见面了
Catwoman. So we meet again.
没错，女超人
So we do,Supergirl.
我是菲比
It's me,Phoebe.
莫妮卡 我能跟你谈一谈吗？
Monica,can I talk to you for a second?
谢谢你帮我找衣服
I appreciate the costume.
你帮他找衣服？
You did this to him?
我觉得他一定会喜欢
I thought he'd love it.
-他喜欢毛毛兔 -那只兔子是棕白相间
-He loves The Velveteen Rabbit. -That rabbit was brown and white.
他们只剩下粉红色的兔子装
It was pink,or no bunny at all.
没有兔子装 他们总是说没有兔子装
No bunny at all. Always no bunny at all!
-你也没有变装？ -不，我有，我扮成钱德
-You didn't dress up either? -Yes,I did. I'm Chandler.
兄弟，发生了什么事？
Dude,what happened?
我怎么会是那个样子？
How is that me?
我是钱德
I'm Chandler.
那真的很像你
That is so you!
-我什么时候会那样？ -我什么时候会那样？
-When have I ever done that? -When have I ever done that?
不给糖就捣蛋
Trick or treat.
-你是最漂亮的芭蕾舞娘 -谢谢
-You're the prettiest ballerina ever. -Thank you.
我该再给你一颗糖果
That deserves another candy.
谢谢
Thank you.
我得说 我该再给你一些糖果
I have to say,that earns "two-two" pieces of candy.
我爱你
I love you!
亲爱的，通通拿去吧
Honey,here,take it all.
莫妮卡，糖果没了
Monica? We need more candy.
-刚刚只来了四个孩子 -我知道
-There's only been four kids. -I know.
但有个孩子说她爱我 于是我全部都给她了
But one said she loved me,so I gave her everything.
难怪你会怀孕
No wonder you're pregnant.
-你扮的是什么？-还记得史波尼克号卫星吗？（前苏联发射）
-What are you supposed to be? -Remember the satellite,Sputnik?
我扮成马铃薯或者说“土豆”…
Well,I'm a potato. Or a "spud"..
这是我的天线
and these are my antenna.
所以史波尼克变成了…
So Sputnik becomes..?
土豆尼克（以“尼克”为后缀表示新鲜事物）
Spud-nik!
哇 原来我不是变装最失败的人
Wow! I don't have the worst costume anymore.
哦，罗斯是坨粪
All right! Ross came as doodie.
-不，我不是粪 -对，你是太空之粪
-No,I'm not doodie. -No,space-doodie.
好吧，我是土豆尼克
Okay,I'm Spud-nik.
-我在模仿史波尼克 -什么是史波尼克？粪团
-You know,like Sputnik. -What's a Sputnik,doodie-man?
嘿，亲爱的
Hey,sweetie.
-你不吻我吗？ -好吧
-Aren't you gonna kiss me? -Okay.
但我吻了你之后 你得告诉我你是谁
But right after,you have to tell me who you are.
-乌苏拉？ -乌苏拉的未婚夫？
-Ursula? -Ursula's fiance?
你是她的妹妹 我刚刚打了我未来小姨子的屁股
You're the sister. I just slapped my future sister-in-law's ass.
你妈妈在这里吗？ 我可以打她的屁股
Is your mother here? I could slap her on the butt.
-我妈自杀死掉了 -看吧，我就知道
-My mother killed herself. -See,and I knew that.
我满身大汗
Now I'm sweating.
我在流汗，看看我 我满身大汗，我该走了
I'm sweating. Now I'm saying look at me,I'm even sweatier. I should go.
不，我们从头来过
No. We'll start over.
-嗨，我是菲比 -我是艾力克
-Hi,I'm Phoebe. -Eric.
-你为什么要那样子看我？ -汗滴到我眼睛里了
-Why are you looking at me like that? -Sweat's burning my eyes.
-谢谢 -拿去吧
-Thank you. -There.
-那是什么？ -我不知道该怎么说
-What are you? -There's no name for it.
我一紧张就会满身大汗
I get nervous,and I sweat like crazy.
-不，我是指你的服装 -我扮成太阳系
-No,I meant your costume. -I'm a solar system.
我的二年级学生帮我变装
My second graders helped.
-我喜欢二年级 -真的吗？
-I love the second grade. -Really?
它比一年级好多了 也比三年级好
It's much better than first grade,and definitely better than third.
你可以玩尔虞我诈 的斗智游戏
With all the politics and the mind games.
-你是做哪一行的？ -我平常是按摩师
-So,what do you do? -I'm a masseuse,by day.
-你不必陪我 -我觉得很开心
-You don't have to stand with me. -I'm having fun.
-我为你跟乌苏拉感到高兴 -我觉得自己很幸运，她太棒了
-I'm excited for you and Ursula. -I feel very lucky. She's great.
-她是最美丽的女人 -谢谢你
-She's the most beautiful woman ever. -Thank you.
-乔伊 -什么事？
-Hey,Joey? -Yeah?
-你常看漫画书吧？ -我是专家
-You read comic books,right? -Exclusively.
如果猫女跟女超人打架 谁会赢呢？
Who would win in a fight,Catwoman or Supergirl?
-当然是猫女 -太棒了
-Catwoman,hands down. -Yeah.
但你跟菲比吗？ 我赌菲比会赢
Between you and Phoebe? I'd give Phoebe the edge.
-什么？真的吗？ -你在开玩笑吗？
-What? Really? -You kidding?
菲比在街上混过，好吗？ 而且她生起气来跟疯婆子一样
Phoebe lived on the street,okay? Plus,she's got a crazy temper.
她没有站在我后面吧？
She's not right behind me,is she?
不，你很安全
No,you're fine.
-我能打倒瑞秋吗？ -我不确定
-Could I take Rachel? -I'm not sure.
什么？少来了，我很凶的
What? Come on,I am tough!
用力打我这里
Punch me here,as hard as you can!
别激动，你为什么那么认真？ 那不重要
Relax. Why are you so serious? It doesn't matter.
真的吗？如果我告诉你 罗斯或钱德能打倒你呢？
Really? What if I told you Ross or Chandler could beat you up?
我会说“拜托，女人家”
I would say,"Woman,please."
乌苏拉的未婚夫真的很帅
Ursula's fiance is really sweet.
-你觉得你能打倒他吗？ -胸口贴着球的那个家伙？
-You think you could take him? -The dude with the balls on his chest?
我想可以
I think so.
但他跟我姐姐在一起做什么？ 他真的太棒了
But what is he doing with my sister? He's so great.
他是老师 他会做义工
He's a teacher,he does volunteer work.
通常我不喜欢会流汗的男人 但我愿意帮他擦汗
Normally,I don't like sweaty guys. But I could just mop him up.
-天啊，菲比 -什么？
-Oh,my God,Phoebe? -What?
-你在暗恋他 -不，我才没有，是你
-You're getting a crush on him. -No,I'm not,you are!
她的脾气来了
Here comes the temper.
不给糖就捣蛋
Trick or treat.
你知道吗？我们没有糖果了 但已经有人去买了
Know what? We're out of candy. But someone went for more.
我改给孩子们钱 但我的钱也都给光了
And I've been giving out money,but I'm out of that too.
-我可以开张支票给你吗？ -好吧
-Can I write you a check? -Okay.
-好吧，你叫什么名字？ -李兰妮马尤拉诺法维奇
-Okay. What's your name? -Lelani Mayolanofavich.
好吧，我会写上 “现金支票”
Okay,I'm just gonna write this out to "cash."
-嗨 -嗨，蒙娜
-Hi. -Hi,Mona.
乔伊一定会很兴奋 他希望你扮成风流护士
Joey's gonna be thrilled. He was hoping you'd be a slutty nurse.
事实上我只是扮成护士
Actually,I'm just a nurse.
你以为我听了会觉得很丢脸 但我已经丢够脸了
You'd think that would embarrass me,but I'm maxed out.
-你来了 -等一下
-You made it. -Wait.
-你是马铃薯？ -喔，我是土豆…
-You're a potato? -Well,I'm a spud..?
-还有天线…你是土豆尼克 -答对了
-And the antenna.. You're Spud-nik! -Yes!
娶她吧
Marry her.
这真的很有趣 罗斯跟钱德打架谁会赢？
Here's a good one. Who'd win a fight between Ross and Chandler?
我没办法回答 钱德是我的老公
I can't answer that. Chandler's my husband.
-罗斯会赢？ -对
-So Ross? -Yeah.
-嘿，美女 -你好，帅哥
-Hey,beautiful. -Hello,handsome.
天啊
Oh,God.
看看你们两个 你们什么时候认识的？
Look at you two. When did you guys meet?
-两个星期前 -就那样？
-Two weeks ago. -That's it?
我知道这听起来很疯狂 我不是个冲动的人，但是…
I know. It sounds crazy,and I'm not impulsive,but..
-我们有很多共通点 -真的吗？
-we have so much in common. -Oh,really?
我们都是老师
We're both teachers.
-我们都参加了和平团（肯尼迪创办的志愿者团体）-真的吗？
-And we were both in the Peace Corps. -Peace Corps,really?
我们在乌拉圭做义工时 只距离两个小镇远，却从来没见过面
When we were building in Uruguay,we were two towns apart and never met.
对，我刚到时那里一片荒芜 但我离开时那里已经是个小镇了
Yeah. It wasn't a town when I got there,but it was a town when I left.
-我们可以去喝一杯吗？ -没问题
-Shall we get me really drunk? -Sure.
你好，粪团
Howdy,doodie.
那真的很有趣
That's funny,yeah.
你是个最幽默的家伙 穿着你太太帮你挑的兔子装
You're the funniest man here in a bunny costume his wife made him wear.
别激动 你看起来有点要化掉了
Relax,man. You're looking a little flushed.
-我们的问题有解了 -什么问题？
-Our question might get answered. -What question?
你跟罗斯打架 谁会赢？
Who could kick whose ass in a fight,you or Ross?
-那不是问题 -你也觉得罗斯会赢？
-There's no question. -So you think Ross too?
-你选罗斯？ -罗斯很强壮
-You picked Ross? -Ross is strong.
他是你们三个之中最壮的 乔伊除外
He's the strongest out of all three of you. Except for Joey.
-我不敢相信你没有选我 -她说的对，我比你壮
-I can't believe you didn't pick me. -She's right. I am stronger.
我要毁了你
I would destroy you.
真的吗？你觉得你比较壮吗？ 你为什么不证明给大家看？
Really? You think you're stronger? Why don't you prove it?
我一定会证明的
I'll prove it like a theorem!
好了，别吵了
All right! Stop it!
别吵了，谁都不准打架
Stop! No one's gonna fight.
大家来这里看人打架 快打给他们看吧
People came to see a fight,let's give them one!
-你们可以比腕力 -听风流护士的话
-You guys could arm-wrestle. -Listen to the slutty nurse.
-你死定了 -是吗？你才死定了
-You're going down. -Oh,yeah? You're going downtown!
说真的 你们的叫阵台词太逊了
Seriously,guys,the trash talk is embarrassing.
甘瑟，你买到糖果了 谢谢你
Gunther,you brought candy. Thank you so much.
-你真的是太棒了 -真的吗？
-You are so sweet. -Really?
跟你在一起的人 会是全世界最幸运的男朋友
You are gonna make some man the luckiest guy in the world.
-我得走了 -不给糖就捣蛋
-Got to go. -Trick or treat.
嗨，拿去吧
Hi! Wow! There you go.
我朋友路易斯说 你会给钱
My friend Lewis told me you were giving out money.
没错，但现在我们有糖果了
We were,but now we've got candy.
我宁愿要钱
I'd rather have the money.
那由不得你来选 万圣节快乐
That's not your choice. Happy Halloween!
这不公平
This isn't fair.
你披上斗篷就能跟别人要东西 那公平吗？
Is it fair that you put on a cape and get stuff?
闭嘴
Shut up!
你才闭嘴
You shut up!
-你不能叫我闭嘴 -我想我刚刚说了
-You can't tell me to shut up. -I think I just did.
我又想说了，闭嘴
And here it comes again. Shut up!
不，我可以，我很厉害的
No,I got it. I'm good. I got it.
等一下，我还有一句话要告诉你 对，闭嘴
Wait,I had one more thing to say. Right. Shut up.
你是个可怕的老女人
You're a mean old woman.
等一下，闭…别哭了
Wait! Shut.. Don't cry!
我去拿支票簿
Let me get my checkbook!
你不必这么做 心地善良才是最重要的
You don't have to do this. The strength inside you means the most.
你既忠心又老实 而且你的品德高贵
You're loyal,you're honest and you have integrity.
那才是我要的男人
That's the strength I want in a man.
那对我来说毫无意义，来吧
That means nothing to me. Come on!
-嗨，骗子 -嘿
-Hi,liar. -Hey.
他会娶你是因为 他以为你说的话是真的
He's marrying you because he thinks the things you were saying were true.
-它们有可能是真的 -但你真的在说谎
-They could be true. -But they're not.
真假只有一线之隔
It's a fine line.
-你为什么要说谎？ -我不知道
-Why are you lying? -I don't know.
他做了那些事，我说我也是 他变得很兴奋，我觉得很好玩
He did this stuff,I said I did it too. He got so excited,it was fun.
你不能那么做 你会毁了他的生活
You can't do this. You're gonna ruin his life.
你为什么那么认真？ 这只是婚姻而已
Why are you taking this so seriously? It's just a marriage.
而且如果我背着他偷人 我可以说那是外遇
Besides,if I cheat on him,I can call it an affair.
亲爱的
Honey?
这是个坏习惯 我要你马上戒烟
It's a disgusting habit,and I want you to quit now!
她帮助很多人戒烟
She's helped so many people quit.
我们得走了
We'd better get going.
-你还得参加教会的聚会 -对
-You have a church group meeting. -Right.
-很高兴能见到你 -我也是
-It was nice meeting you. -You too.
乌苏拉 我很高兴今晚能见到你
And,Ursula,it was really nice meeting you tonight!
快来吧，兔子大战粪团 我们在等你
Come on! Bunny versus doodie. We're waiting!
好吧，一次决胜负 赢的人是英雄
Okay,guys. One match,winner take all.
等一下，冠军有什么奖品？
Wait. What does the winner get?
-骄傲 -跟自尊
-Pride. -And dignity.
好吧，你说了算
Okay,if you say so.
好吧，就位，预备，开始
All right,ready,set,go!
-加油 -加油
-Come on! -Come on!
-他们都很壮 -或是一样逊
-Wow,they're both really strong. -Or equally weak.
天啊 钱德露出他的性感表情了
Oh,God. Chandler's making his sex face.
-你累了吗？ -不，我可以撑一整天
-So you getting tired? -No. I could do this all day.
对，我也是
Yeah. Me too.
-但我有点累了 -天啊，我累坏了
-Getting a little tired,though. -God,I'm exhausted.
我开始泄气了，好吗？ 蒙娜就站在那里
This is starting to look bad for me,okay? Mona's standing right there.
她在跟乔伊说话 你得让我赢
She's talking to Joey! You gotta let me win!
让我赢 我太太以为我无能
Let me win. My wife thinks I'm a wimp.
至少你还有太太 我离婚了，还搞大别人的肚子
At least you have a wife. I get divorces and knock people up.
我打扮的跟个粪团一样
And I'm dressed as doodie.
-你是土豆尼克 -少来了，我们要骗谁呢？我是粪团
-You're Spud-nik. -Come on,who we kidding? I'm doodie.
拜托，她在看我
Please? She's watching.
-好吧 -谢谢
-Fine. -Thanks.
-不 -太棒了
-Oh,no. -Oh,yeah!
我的英雄
My hero!
你是个怪女人
You're a weird lady.
乌苏拉忘了拿皮包
Ursula said she left her purse.
这真的是太好了 里面放了她祈祷团朋友的电话
What a relief. It has the numbers for her prayer chain.
是啊
I'm sure it does.
我们婚礼上见了
Guess I'll see you at the wedding.
我想我没办法 去参加婚礼
I don't think I'm gonna make it to the wedding.
祝你们好运
I wish you all the luck in the world.
我还要给你 一个小建议
And I also want to give you a little piece of advice..
我会给每对新人 这样的建议
that I give to everyone who's getting married.
别相信你的太太
Don't trust your wife.
我想我们会没事的
I think we'll be okay.
真的太完美了 她一直为我保持处子之身
It's so perfect,and she's been saving herself for me.
-我不能让你这么做，她在说谎 -什么？
-I can't let you do this. She's lying. -What?
她在说谎 我想我可以证明，对不起
She is lying. And I bet I could prove it. Excuse me.
好吧，没有祈祷团的电话
Okay. Yeah,not a prayer chain.
但它看起来像是 银行的平面图
But what looks like a detailed drawing of a bank floor plan.
这是她在餐厅 当女服务生的铭牌
Here's the name tag from where she works as a waitress.
她不是老师，她是女服务生
Not a teacher,a waitress.
这里，她总是会撒这个谎
Here,she always lies about this.
-她跟你说她几岁了？ -她说她25岁
-How old did she say she was? -She told me she was 25.
我真的不想拿给你看
I almost don't want to show you.
记住，我比她年轻一分钟
Just remember,I'm a minute younger.
我太笨了
I am so stupid.
她当然不是老师
Of course she's not a teacher.
根本不会有 “超机密儿童间谍学校”
There's no such thing as a "Top Secret School for the Children of Spies."
不，你不笨
No,you're not stupid.
我不聪明
I'm not smart.
我只是很想 冲动一下
I just wanted so much to be impulsive for once.
-找一点浪漫 -很好
-To be romantic. -Good.
你应该要冲动跟浪漫 只是你找错对象了
You should be impulsive and romantic. You did it with the wrong person.
-什么？ -那真的很奇怪，你们长得那么像
-What? -It's weird,two people look so alike.
却完全不一样
And so different.
艾力克，我们走吧
Eric! Let's go!
-我得去解决问题 -没错，你该那么做
-Better go deal with it. -Yeah,you should.
快点，我得去祷告
Hurry up! I gotta pray!
我得给那孩子50块 他才不哭
I had to give the kid 50 bucks to stop crying.
那还不赖
That's not bad.
我还得当他的女朋友 陪他走一段路
I also had to go to a few houses as his girlfriend.
我真的不会应付小孩子
I am awful with children.
你跟孩子们相处的很好 只是小孩子在万圣节都会抓狂
You're good with kids. They're just crazy on Halloween.
他们贪心地 想多拿一些糖果
They're all greedy,hopped up on sugar.
-就那样？ -当然
-That's all it is? -Absolutely.
万圣节是最糟糕的 除了圣诞节，还有他们的生日
Halloween is the worst. Except for Christmas. And their birthdays.
他们在夏天也会抓狂
They get crazy during the summer too.
还有他们肚子饿 跟想睡觉的时候
And any time they're hungry or sleepy.
小孩子很难缠 祝你好运
Kids are tough. Good luck with that.
听着，我很遗憾你输了
Look,I'm sorry you lost.
我得告诉你一个秘密 我故意让他赢
I got a secret for you. I let him win.
那是秘密还是谎话？
Was that a secret,or a lie?
-不，我让他…罗斯 -什么事？
-No,I let him.. Ross? -Yeah?
麻烦你告诉她 我故意让你赢
Would you tell her I let you win,please?
钱德“故意让我赢”
Chandler "let me win."
不，钱德真的好壮 我的手好酸喔，护士
No,Chandler's really strong. My arm is so sore. Oh,nurse?
我很强壮，我要证明给你看
I am strong. I'll show you.
钱德，拜托
Chandler,please.
怎么了？你害怕吗？
What's the matter? Scared?
来吧，大兔子
Let's go,big bunny!
一，二，三，开始
One,two,three. Go!
我要去自杀
I'm gonna kill myself!